A Register of the Walter Reade Hardin Jr. Collection 1934-1952
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Walter Reade Hardin Jr. Collection 1934-1952
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms2003-027
1 container; 0.1 cu. ft.
Materials collected by a Virginia Tech cadet and band member during his college years. Includes mementos, photographs and newspaper clippings.
Donor
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Walter Reade Hardin Jr. Collection was donated to the Special Collections in 1985. Donated together with the papers of Fields M. Young--Hardin's grandfather--these materials were separated during the processing of the Young Papers and assigned a separate manuscript number.
Biographical/Historical Information
Walter Reade Hardin Jr., Virginia Tech graduate and U. S. Army veteran, was born on February 20, 1917. The son of Walter Reade and Mattie Young Hardin, he attended Virginia Tech as a cadet majoring in business administration. A member of the band, as well as the Bachelor, Cotillion and Roanoke clubs, Hardin graduated in 1941. During World War II, he served as a captain in the U. S. Army. In 1952, he married Mary McIntosh Holland. Hardin died on July 17, 1985 and is buried in the Christ Church Episcopal Cemetery, Eastville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains materials collected by Virginia Tech student and band member Walter Reade Hardin Jr. Apparently removed from a scrapbook, the collection contains a number of mementos associated with Virginia Tech social affairs (including dances and concerts); various photos of cadet and band groups, classmates, and events surrounding the 1938 homecoming football game with the University of Virginia; and a small assortment of newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
Arranged by document type, then chronologically.
Contents List
- Mementos (Folder 1)
  - Souvenir football program: Jefferson vs. Woodrow Wilson and VMI Freshmen vs VPI Freshmen Nov 10 1934
  - Sons of Rhythm / Sigman Tau Sigma concert contract Feb 16 1935
  - Lions Minstrels show ticket Apr 16 1936
  - Cotillion Club dance program Oct 1937
  - Jooss European Ballet program Feb 23 1938
  - Cotillion Club dance program Oct 1939
  - Bachelor Club membership certificate 1941
  - Duke Ellington dance ticket n.d.
  - Mill Mountain incline ticket n.d.
  - Luther J. Hargroves calling card n.d.
  - Tommy Dorsey concert pass out check n.d.
  - Guy Lombardo concert pass out check n.d.
  - Cotillion Club membership certificate n.d.
  - Crismond's Log Cabin "dine and dance" business card n.d.
  - "A Full House" play program n.d.
- Photographs (Folder 1)
  - Walter Reade Hardin Jr. dormitory room 1937-1938, [2 items]
  - Walter Reade Hardin Jr. in cadet band uniform 1937-1938
  - First division, freshman barracks no. 1 1937-1938
  - Drum section for Sunday afternoon concerts Spring 1938
  - VPI rat parade Sep 17 1938
  - Cadet Miller and the "Old Lady" (cannon) Sep 1938
  - Walter Reade Hardin Jr. Sep 1938
  - Cadet Miller in dormitory room Sep 1938
  - Walter Reade Hardin Jr. with cannon Sep 1938
  - Cadet wall decoration Sep 1938
  - George Wyman Oct 14 1938
  - E. F. Schoch on Barracks No. 1 fire escape Oct 14 1938
  - Homecoming bonfire Oct 14 1938, [3 items]
  - Campus homecoming displays Oct 14-15 1938, [6 items]
  - Cadet and band group photos c. 1938, [6 items]
- Newspaper clippings (Folder 1)
  - "Mary McIntosh Holland Engaged to Marry Walter Reade Hardin, Jr." - Norfolk Virginian-Pilot Feb 24 1952
  - "Week-end to Bring V.P.I. Midwinters" n.d.
  - "Jefferson High School Seniors..." n.d.
  - "Most Beautiful Senior" n.d.
  - "Ella Jean Griffin" n.d.
  - "Long and Two Shorts" [J. W. Lewis, Jimmy H. Hutchinson, W. C. Vawter] n.d.
  - "Sprit of V. M. I." n.d.
  - ""Reade Hardin... will spend Thanksgiving with his mother" n.d.
  - [Unidentified woman's portrait] n.d.